recording
and I would like to welcome everyone
again for joining us for this seminar on
the adversary engagement ontology
as uh as the announcement mentioned this
uh project is
a collaboration between miter say lab
and a number of other
organizations we just released the a
beta version of the address of
Engagement ontology and we hope that the
seminar today that's who's a talks today
will provide you with
some uh with an overview of why there is
a need for an adversary engagement
ontology
what is adversary engagement in terms of
cyber deception ending at all
and how
one might be able to leverage AEO
adversary engagement application
ontology
to attack at this engagement planning uh
operations and
uh
and uh intelligence collection after
operations after interactions today we
are lucky to have a wonderful lineup of
speakers
we have uh Maritza
Marvel
I hope I'm not mispronouncing uh her
name Marita is
uh from
the miter engage tune
after which uh Corey Hall the project
leader for cyber domain ontology will be
presenting an overview of what the Cyber
domain ontology the unified cyber
ontology and the application ontology
such as case and AE are all about
and this will be followed by a brief
introduction statement from Alex Nelson
from nest
who has been contributing to this
project uh with
uh who had quite a bit of valuable
feedback as well as guidance
and then
last but definitely not least
uh the sale team will be presenting the
adversary engagement ontology uh its
current version its structured and its
use case through example scenarios
now with that
um I would like to invite merita to
uh see if she can join her is share her
screen and do a quick sound check
can you hear me I can hear you can you
hear me
I think you need to give me permission
to share because uh disabled screen
sharing
it's now enabled
boom look at that okay hang on
and the floor is yours
can you see slide
oh did that work
yep excellent all right Martin everyone
knows just to let you know just delay uh
will be made up with the buffer time
we've added at the end of the schedule
so all of the presentations will retain
their original duration and length
perfect okay
um let me just all right hang up okay
all right so hi good morning everyone
um
I wanted to spend a few minutes today
talking a little bit about the way that
miter thinks about adversary engagement
and uh to talk a bit about the indeed
framework and
um where it came from and where we're
going with it and the resources that are
available through it so
um my name is I just got married that
might have known me as murder Market
um I switched because I forget half the
time what my new last name is um
so uh starting off with some definition
so the way that we Define all of these
various pieces is we like to talk about
revealing and concealing facts and
fiction
um this is a concept you
if you've cyber denial the question in
counter deception a book that came out
um a little ways back at this point they
have a great broad chart in there where
they really break out these concepts by
the same lines and so um we thought it
was really important to refer back to
that book and kind of make that the
basis of a lot of the things
um and how we talk about and how we
Define these various Concepts so um
quick shout out to that book and again
it's fiber denial question encounter
deception uh written by a number of
minor folks including Frank deck and
Kristen Heckman and Alex though and it's
a really great read and if you haven't
read it I highly recommend it so
starting with some definition so we talk
about fiber denial those are revealing
conviction to prevent or impair an
adversary of operation on the other side
of that we have private detection here
we're talking about feeling the fact in
fiction the mislead or confused and then
most importantly in from engages
perspective is taking these two things
together coupling them with strategic
planning and Analysis and talking about
that as adversary engagement and we
think this term is really important
um because one of the things we see all
the time is there's a lot of confusion
there's a lot of
um it's misunderstandings around the
word deception when you go into
government and DOD spaces military
deception as sort of very specific
meanings and very specific context in
the private sector you know there's a
lot of confusion with is deception lying
is deception uh misinformation right no
one wants to be on the cover of the
Washington Post
um with my company does misinformation
right that's not what anyone wants so
there's a lot of just um
like I said misunderstandings tracked
around using cyber deception and so for
this reason we really like to talk about
things as adversary engagement because
we feel like that really gets to the
heart of what we're trying to do and
also takes away some of that confusion
around the negativity associated with
perfection
so now that we've sort of defined
um the Nile interception and adversary
engagement talked about the concealing
and revealing fact I wanted to give a
couple of examples of what they could
really look like and what this means and
how this might show up in other things
outside of just the fiber Realm
a little there we go so um I can't see
anyone but we'll do a show in Virtual
hand
um even though I can't believe that's
okay
um who has ever put a this house
protected by or beware of Dom's fine out
front of their house
right so that's a great example of
revealing facts and telling something
that is true about that house or about
you know that business or whatever it is
what about put their lights on a timer
when they went on vacation or left music
playing when you left the house
well that's an example of revealing
effect no one's actually home but you're
in some way
um you know making it look like
someone's home I like to think about the
the scene in Home Alone when the they
set up that whole big party and they
have all the it looks like there's a
whole group of people in there and it's
just that one little kid
what about hidden a key in a fake rock
what's concealing a fact
and finally you forgot to write a paper
in school so you write the first page
only you staple it to a bunch of blank
pages you rip off the blank pages and
then you tell your people I don't know
what happened they must have gotten
[ __ ] no that one's just me okay
um well that would be concealing
affected and since we're doing this at a
university I don't endorse this
um but all these different things are
just meant to sort of show how do we
think about concealing and revealing
facts and fiction and as we go on we can
think a little bit more about what does
that look like in fiber
I just want to provide a couple other um
sort of mental models to wrap our brains
around how this could look and what the
usefulness are what the youthfulness is
of some of these things so
um
let's talk about aware of Waldo puzzle
right in Where's Waldo your job if you
haven't seen one of these before right
is to find the little guy with the hat
and I meant to find him before this and
I totally forgot to so he's here
somewhere
um but what makes it really hard to find
Waldo has nothing to do with Waldo and
everything to do with Waldo's
environment right you have the keys to
the kingdom if you will and yet you
still can't find Waldo because there's
all the colors they're similar patterns
there's lots of noise in the same way
when we think about our cyber
environments right now if there's an
intrusion and someone get through all of
our layers of you know defense and depth
and they make it through to have the
keys to the kingdom if you will
um if one right they have access to data
they have access to you know crown
jewels and critical asset
um but how could we turn the table how
can we bad ambiguity to the environment
make that process of I'm in but I don't
necessarily have a full understanding or
a full picture easily quickly and how do
I kind of ramp up and adjust that
ambiguity on the flip side there might
also be times where we want to lower
that ambiguity right so if we're setting
up Honeypot or if we're setting up areas
of our Network that we know are highly
monitored or we have suppliers or
whatever it might be then maybe we want
to turn down the ambiguity in those
environments make our adversary feel a
little bit more comfortable like you're
going to go that way lead them towards
the things that don't matter in a way
for nothing to do so we can start
thinking about this as a knob of how do
we increase the ambiguity to protect
what's valuable and decrease the
ambiguity in places that we want to move
the adversary towards
um so here I have two pictures of a park
your job is to get from the side of the
park Iran to the other side of the park
um again I can't actually become any
presentation mode be any hand but um
let's pretend that you guys are raising
him how many people are going to take
the path on the right
and how many people are going to take
the path on the left so
um most times when I can see the
audience uh the answer here is that most
people are going to take
um that path in the left why it's well
lit it has a it has nice clear guide
rails right I can see where I'm going
and I feel more comfortable never have I
had someone say I'm going to across the
graph right just the fact that I put a
path in front of you and said get from
one side to the other most are going to
gravitate towards that path so how do we
again think about that same thing in the
Fiber space how do we create a well-lit
comfortable path so that the adversary
will move in the ways that we want them
to and those are the places that we're
going to again be
um high levels of monitoring we're going
to have tripwires we're going to feel
like we're well defended and make the
places that we we don't want them to go
near our Crown duels or around the
places that you know that system that's
been on the network for forever and you
know we just can't patch it because it
was made by one manufacturer that is now
out of business and it's critical to our
manufacturing company and I've seen that
happen in the real world
um how do we make that look like the
dark and scary pop and make the the area
that we can defend look like that knife
well lit path
so we'll talk a little bit more now
about
um now that we have sort of an
understanding of what why we want to do
this and what this could look like about
the goals of adversary engagement and
one of the big principles behind miter
engage is that everything needs to be
goal driven
um oftentimes when we're talking to
organizations that are trying to start
using deception or adversary engagement
and we ask why if the answer is
something along the lines of
sounds good it sounds useful it sounds
cool
um and it's not goal driven right if we
think about the history of detection
from a military perspective no military
commander in in history whatever say
they're using deception for deception's
sake deception is always about having a
goal and it's the tool you're using to
get there and so we like to adopt that
same model when it comes to adversary
engagement
so we break things down into three kind
of categories of goals the first one is
we want it with both adversaries that
are already operating on our Network by
triggering High Fidelity alert this is
kind of probably the most obvious use
case of that with their engagement is
where a lot of the vendor space is
playing
um and it's one of the sort of easy
entry points because it kind of it just
makes sense when we think about what
we're trying to do and how we're trying
to do it right you can put deceptive
documents that when you open them we'll
send an alert you could have detective
users or video users on your network but
if someone tried to use a password or
login at that user you get an alert you
can put decoy credentials around
um around an environment and if one of
those credentials gets you you have a
high fidelity alert right so think about
these different ways that we can have a
high level of confidence that if
something is triggering that alert
something bad is happening
um one of the interesting things there
as well is that even when it's not
something really bad so for example
those decoy documents are even putting a
decoy Network there so let's say on our
CEO desktop we put a share that says you
know my tax document or something like
that and we have a bunch of what looks
like personal data well even if a
legitimate employee is touching that
chair it still probably warrants the
conversation of why are you snooping
around the CEO's desktop so really
providing us with not just an
understanding of what's bad but also
helping to inform maybe any
um Behavior that's just unwanted
the second one is about affecting an
adversary type of operation in some way
that protects your organization by
either decreasing the damage or scope of
a compromise reducing future targeting
or disrupting malicious operation
to be so personally I think this is
where some of the real power of AdvoCare
engagement lies I think it's an area
that the vendor space is not fully
started playing in yet I think there's
some more advanced folks who are a bit
more mature and are starting to sort of
look at what this would look like in our
networks but we're kind of far the
community from that adoption of using
adversary engagement to do things like
increase ambiguity and environments or
um you know add uncertainty to an
environment or just kind of create noise
and backgrounds in an environment
and finally
um we have a set of goals that involved
a listening intelligence from an
adversary based on your sort of
contextualized timely relevant attack
circuit
um there's a number of different folks I
think are playing in the space typically
this is being done by threat and fell
teams who are not
um kind of involved with the production
networks and production security so this
is typically
um and sort of best practices for the
sort of Intel of the patient to happen
on isolated networks that are either
unattributed From Any Given organization
or potentially look like the
organization that is trying to collect
the threat intelligence there's some
great examples out there of organization
generating threat intelligence in this
way
I think one of the most public examples
is HSBC
um has a threat Intel theme and they
spoke at RFA last year
um as well as new con last year
um about their work using fiber
deception and adversary engagement
through illicit threat intelligence
um and this is actually I'll let me go
back a little bit about kind of where
miter got started but it actually
involved this threat intelligent
solicitation Faith so we got started in
adversary engagement about about 10
years ago at this point because we had
too much time spent an indicator from
others that weren't always relevant to
us it was difficult to discover much on
a production Network there was little to
no information on post compromise PCP
tactics techniques and procedures and
there were a few options for post
compromised infinite response so we
started to put a lot of effort into
changing the game and for us adversary
engagement was the way to do that and so
we ran an initial
um adversary engagement operation as a
result of a real compromise and from
that we then started to run a number of
operations for the subsequent years
um in attributed environment
unattributed environment we had a number
of different rigs that we would use in
order to be able to maintain these
operations
um and were able to generate a lot of
really valuable threat religion and so
actually one of our biggest sort of ways
of sharing the threat intelligence out
with the community has been through
attack so obviously today attack is much
bigger than than just accepted but the
initial humble beginnings of attack with
most of that intelligent was coming
through the adversary engagement
operations that miter was running at the
time we weren't talking about doing that
with their engagement and so we were
able to sort of share that information
out through with that without having to
talk about how we were getting that
intelligent through these operations but
that was sort of attack on the Lord
didn't but as I said attack is much
bigger today and has a lot more sources
um than just minor obviously
um but that was that kind of our our
Focus initially was was on threat
intelligent solicitation via adversary
engagement
um but one thing that's really important
to note is that adversary engagement is
not static adversaries change over time
and organization changes over time
Global events change over time and
because of that there's sort of this
wave of where your priorities are so for
example reminders beginning it was
really important for us to understand
what was going on we really needed to be
able to understand that threat landscape
but over time that might change and one
thing that's really important is making
sure that we're kind of constantly
understanding what is my goal today and
how do I make sure that I'm constantly
adapting and adjusting my engagement so
that I'm meeting whatever goal that I
have today
um and one of the things that sort of
this relies on is being the whole thing
as a goal driven process and that was
really the impotence for us developing
miter engage and wanting to put
something out into the community because
we realized that this is not like other
defense and depth Technologies right so
antivirus EDR you can kind of deploy it
and walk away
and you don't really need to put a lot
of thought into the process or changing
it over time but adversary engagement
does require that you do that and so we
wanted to create miter engage in order
to help with that
so this is the miter engage Matrix and I
have to apologize to everyone if you go
onto our website we just found out there
is an update
um over the weekend that caused a bunch
of our JavaScript break we are fixing it
um all of the data is available and I'll
pop the link in the chat so you can get
the spreadsheet of data and hopefully
very soon we will have all the
JavaScript apparently there was a
back-end change that happened and that
we weren't aware of so it is not
interactive at the moment but
ultimately
ordinarily you can you can go on the
website and click through all of these
different buckets and read more about
what sort of how we Define that specific
um piece of the Matrix some places where
we've seen references to it and things
like that but for now I Want to Break
Down The Matrix into how this really can
be used as a planning tool so on the end
we have what we talk about is our
strategic action this is what helps us
bookend our operation with strategic
planning and Analysis
in the middle we have engagement action
so this is how you're driving progress
towards the defender's strategic goal if
we start slicing the other way across
the top we have goals so these are the
big outcomes you're trying to achieve
and what's really important here is
everything is always viewed downwards
through those goals it really helps us
remember that this is a goal driven
process
one level down from that we that we have
our approaches so that's the main the
means that we by which you're making
progress
um you can sort of think of this as
analogous to a tactic an attack
um the reason it's just not the word
tactic is that when we're mapping
between a path and
um engage we're not talking about attack
tactics and engage tactics
and then finally one level down from
that we have activities so these are the
concrete technique that you're going to
use to make progress um and to really go
out your approach again this is similar
to a technique but for that same reason
we didn't want to use the same word
each of the activities in the center
um in in the engagement activities and
those are each map
s the way we think about about this is
that when an adversary does something so
pick a given decode and attack there is
some vulnerability that that exposes and
we can take advantage of that through an
Engaged through an Engaged activity so
for example
um fishing is one of the activities in
um sorry one of the technique there you
go I said there are different words and
I'm still making them a lot
um is one of the techniques in attack
when an adversary conduct fishing
operation they lose control of the yeah
the email that they are sending right if
it's a phishing email they have to send
it into your space they have no idea who
is on the other end actually clicking it
whether it's a real person whether it's
actually in a production Network
um and so the deception opportunity the
engagement opportunity is that you can
use things like lures you can use things
like Persona and so that's how we sort
of think about mapping all of these and
so you'll see on the attack website that
you're sorry on the engagement website
that we have all of these different
things that are all mapped back so you
can start to plan out you know these are
the ecos and attack that I'm most I'm
worried about and here's my engagement
space given that
um one thing to note is that engage is
not meant to be viewed as a finished
product we don't want to tell you how to
shrink wrap your engagement operations
because then they're not really going to
be useful for the community what we're
really trying to present is an
deductible set of guide rails to help
the community start the path forward
we have a number of different different
sort of themes of content and again it's
really all starting with our operation
how do we help the community to also
adopt the tech this technology space in
a way that is effective and most
productive
so this is going to be really quick I
just want to share a couple quick
thoughts on the future of adversary
engagement
um the miter as you can see sort of has
had a long history with it as I already
told I talked with part of that for us
we really want to help the community to
better use this technology and we're
really spending a lot of time and focus
on kind of helping this get out into the
public and and helping other folks be
able to use the technology that we used
for a long time
um for us we think that you know fiber
Avenue their never-ending stream and we
really do need
a killer companies below the fiber
poverty line are in real trouble and
their insecurities if everyone's
insecurity
um and threat intelligence threat to
intellectual property uh and critical
infrastructure right level of national
security threat
nope I just lost my little book you
think there we go
um and really ultimately we want to know
how do we look at the different problems
helping small companies helping um sort
of with direct intellectual property and
critical infrastructure and overall
drive up the cost while driving down the
value of adversary fiber operations and
this is really the focus for engage
um in the years to come
so we hypothesized that we can scale
this with collaboration and we really
believe that that's what's most
important we have a number of things
that we're doing to try to Foster that
collaboration this being a great example
of it today but we really want to help
though how do we go from adversary
engagement at an individual organization
maybe even looking at what this looks
like when a whole industry is
um participating in adverse or
engagement and you're really having
those
um more tailored and kind of
campaign-like structures so that you can
really help protect not just the
organizations that are able to do this
but all the different organizations the
craft and Industry that's a quick little
sneak peek of some of the things that
engage in thinking about right now and
the last thing I'll end on is we are
um about to have sort of our first set
of beta runs of our engaged in a box
this is a non-technical train the
trainer kit designed to help
organizations think differently about
adversary engagement who will actually
be at RFA in a couple weeks with one of
these get to talk about what we're
trying to do and it's really to help
more organizations be able to start
participating in using this technology
and to start thinking about how we can
make this kind of a more strategic
action that we can participate in to
help secure our our company our critical
infrastructure and our intellectual
property
um and with that I will I think I've
used up all my time so I will hand it
over back to I apologies
I think
for me
I hope everyone can hear me now I'm I'd
like to thank you merita this is a
wonderful presentation we are holding q
and aim for the end of the seminar uh at
this point I would like to ask for it
all the publicly for uh the Cyber domain
ontology project to join us
um
[Music]
thank you
yes
okay
you have to sign in here
very well
um
this is
going to take just a moment to set up no
worries
what
happened
okay
and if you just create your name right
yes
[Music]
thank you thank you very much
and great that all of yours great thank
you guys so much
and I can
wonderful thank you so much Miranda for
taking the time to talk to everybody
about the adversary engagement work that
you're doing so I hope everybody you
know was able to learn some things there
uh make sure that you prepare a lot of
questions from Loretta you know so
um again thanks for the opportunity to
come here to University of New Haven
um it's always a pleasure to come here
and work with the faculty and students
on different projects so straight to be
back thank you for hosting it and
and so today I I wanted to share a
couple remarks about an open source
project that I'm
a cyber lonely on polishing project
that's just a little bit about me I work
in the Meyer corporations and a
non-profit organization that supports
our federal government
and I uh one of the roles that I have
there is I'm a project leader of miter's
work at the Department of Defense cyber
crime Center so I appreciate my
colleagues from the dod cybercrime
Center and from this and for Meyer
joining us today online
and uh so a couple of things I've got
work experience across the cycle domain
uh just over 20 years of experience and
one of the things that I do uh in part
time is I I run a volunteer technologist
team at watching International which
creates Technologies for law enforcement
investigators around the world to
investigate crimes against children and
then finally I get the honor to serve as
the project chair for the Linux
foundation's cyber domain on College
projects
right so um Baseline everybody when we
talk about ontologies the monitor
Frameworks for representing shareable
and reusable knowledge across the domain
so like in the Cyber domain here like
just show a hands how many people work
in the Cyber domain are learning domain
okay pretty much everybody now the
problem is is the Cyber domain is very
Broad and I would argue that there are
at least several dozen different areas
of practice within the Cyber domain and
within each of those areas
we have our own unique language so maybe
like average of Engagement
uh even right at her team that are
working adversary engagement they still
get to borrow from
you know from a language of thousands of
Concepts that most cyber practitioners
would agree upon but then Within action
there's a specific language that's
formed to other uh uh other experts in
other areas of the Cyber domain
and so what design we're going oncology
project is all about is developing a
family of ideologies
um and so I'm going to talk about some
of these uh but some of these
non-publishers include what we call the
unified cyber oncology because our
middle oncology the case ontology is our
additional forensics oncology and then
today the team here at the University
okay so let's let's think about this in
a different way
um everybody here speaks English
now how many of you have traveled abroad
to other countries where English is also
been okay most of us right so when you
go from from the United States to the UK
there's a lot of shared language
Concepts or you can walk into a bar and
you can have a great conversation with
them
but somewhere in that conversation
they're going to start talking about
Concepts that you have no idea about
and so they may say something like oh
hey you know I'm gonna go back to my
flights
what the heck is a flag
and you have to you know you have to
maybe ask for some clarification you've
never heard that well in the United
States that's not perfect right and so I
got a list of of those like different
concepts and this is the same problem
that we have of course
now I wonder if you know like a specific
example here here on on this side we
thought uh the left area
as the fact of the cycle operations
maybe like Network designs uh and then
we got digital forensics on the other
side the thing about like legal
processes
and in both of these uh in both of these
areas I was just saying that there are
two two different organizations
um they may both employ visual forensic
examiners
so on the left hand side when you're
trying to detect and respond to
incidents at your local forensic
examiner is going to go through and
they're going to say something like hey
it's forensics they're running instant
response here's what I found I think
something illegal happened here they're
gonna go to their bosses into their
legal counsel and I'm going to say maybe
we should try to like probably you know
get some good government to help
prosecute this
and so they call that local police
department the local police department
sends their digital forensics and family
and they say oh hey you know well I need
to acquire forensic images from the
company I need to use my tools and
processes and basically knew everything
that you already did plus a little bit
more so give me all of your data
um and everything that I can do has to
be
legally offensive one repeal
uh because their work is going to lead
possibly the courtroom and testimony
which will then hopefully lead to
prosecution
and so even though forensic examiners we
work across these two they still operate
uh under uh different concepts and
different process
so when we go back to thinking about
these uh this cyber domain of discourse
the language that we all see
there's a lot of shares I were doing
Concepts thousands of effects
and then we've got these unique
applications
I'm going to go out adversary engagement
about digital forensics think about
instant response
and so those communities are
practitioners have to inherit the
concepts from the shared domain
so let me pull this out a little bit
more
so I mentioned one of the anthologies
that is is within the Cyber domain
oncology project is called the unified
cyber ontology
this is our project's middle oncology so
this is where we express and document
let's just say 80 of the concepts in the
Cyber domain of discourse and so these
are Concepts like a file
an IP address
and many many many more
and
um those things are what we call
observables
now there's a number of other Concepts
in here like a location or the concept
of a pattern of a cool invigoration
of data marketing we've assessed that
all of these Concepts up here are
something or they're Concepts that are
agree upon no matter what area of the
Cyber domain you work in
they can inherit these Concepts and then
reuse them in adverse navigation
so I want to just highlight you know a
few other application specific domains
just kind of show you how quickly we can
start to understand all these different
areas of practice within cyber so I
mentioned digital forensics the original
project science we have with the case on
policy for that and today we're going to
hear about the adversary engagement or
your denial Inception but there's all
these other things like cyber threat
intelligence power analysis advisors
management automating wallability
research defensive cyber operations and
on and on and on and on
so what we're trying to do here is a
cyber building ontology project is to
identify
uh practitioners
in each of these areas and then work
with them over time this this is like
over the years
to identify
the practitioners to make sure that
there's at least a small industry and
that there's some agreement about the
about the taxonomy or the language that
they use within that sub domain and then
we organize them and we invite them to
come under the cyber building oncology
umbrella and we start to documents and
that's exactly what we did was engaged
and we started with Beretta and her
team's work over many many years and
their collaborations with many
researchers vendors and practitioners
and they finally said hey we've got
engaged it's it's a it's a it's a
taxonomy at the end of the day that
expresses all those leading Concepts
and so we said well maybe it's time that
we can Implement an application oncology
that inherits from the universe
and so the point is a different way
we have the unified cyber ontology to
start middle oncology
and application oncology so they inherit
these common Concepts from the UCO
and uh and then when we look at the
application oncologies these are the
things that were that we're working
towards right now we've got one for
digital forensics this is key the case
ontology we have a brand new one uh for
uh deception and average that's an
aeonology and a couple of the things
that we're working on behind the scenes
were supply chain risk cyber threat
intelligence
so now we're also working to bring on
board another uh group from Asia who's
working on an oncology for pharmacy
hours
now we oftentimes will run into
organizations
where they say well you know this is
great and everything but I've got some
Concepts that I don't want to put in
Poland here uh for whatever reason it
could be proprietary or national
security related and the great thing
about this architecture with this with
the middle domain ontology and
application anthologies is that you can
very easily create your own application
oncology which inherits from the middle
oncology and then you can also borrow
from all the public Concepts in the
published application on colleges that
we have
uh so where is this where is this
leading right so so we want this project
to help the entire industry right so so
um I've got these gold lines up here
that help us sort of think through
um the the mission integration between
these different areas of cyber security
practice so let's just start with supply
chain risk I guess it's up to the buy
chain risk is is looking and saying hey
um yeah I'm building something I'm
delivering something there's business
process
and perhaps there's a cyber
vulnerability to somewhere in there well
we didn't know about that and we made
hopefully more humidity back that
mitigation May cost a lot of money
okay so it's not maybe something that
you can go do immediately so in that
regard
uh the fact of the vulnerability is
probably something that you want to
protect or you want to deny that facts
from an adversary Now where's that that
brings an opportunity for a cyber denial
operation
alert then leads to well guess what
cyber threat intelligence about the
adversary
uh it also provides an opportunity for
digital forensics okay for digital
transition instant response and all the
legal process and all the stuff that
we're talking about and a digital
forensics that provides a technical
evidence that informs anonymous
right so in the real world these
practitioners have to work together
but for them to work together more
efficiently to interoper in the future
at all their tools and the processor
operate we have to have this organized
cyber building of discourse and that's
how the ability law school together here
all right and then uh this is an open
source project it's really important
that we have Community contributions
that we have good governance and
processes
under the Linux foundation with three
different uh committees number one we
have a project steering committee which
I have the honor of serving as the chair
for and I following Alex Nelson this
audience he's also a member of this area
committee
uh we have the ontology committee and
then we have an option
and so these are fairly straightforward
names to help us kind of understand the
purposes uh but the Syrian committee is
really about kind of providing that
tactical governance
um it's what interacts with the Linux
foundations that's the Strategic
Direction organizes resources and
manages providing life cycles
depending on politics that committee is
about adjudicating and implementing
changes to all of the project
oncologists uh it meets monthly for
oncology engineering reviews provides
project software and documentation and
then lastly there's the adoption today
and the adoption committee works with
oncology at the doctors worldwide so if
you have a product or research effort
underway you could reach out to the
adoption committee and say hey like did
you have some automation for me to
validate my UCL Json absolutely and so
we can point that to you
um you could also contribute your
research outputs or your open resource
tools to the adoption today
you have a really simple process in
GitHub uh for you to submit a change
request and that will go to the ontology
committee the Anthology Community will
generally very quickly respond and make
sure that the concepts that you need are
then uh put into the oncology in a way
um that is is that is or has been
reviewed probably by all of the
stakeholders
so
um one of the things that's important
here is to be able to start with a new
effort to say like the adversary
engagement on apology
you know when we think about granuary
apology we need to put it through a
maturity process
and and
um so we've been thinking a lot about
this and
um
so so the maturity model that we have uh
this that's uh
uh
near uh but we're getting ready to to
present this
foreigntology effort in a certain area
uh within cyber and I want to include my
little application oncology within the
family of oncologists okay you know I'm
going to come now you're going to make
us aware of your project and you know
eventually you know you become a
candidate project and then eventually
you'll move through this with maturity
model being an approved project a
validated project a formally managed
project and then a formal government
project
and so this allows uh like research
teams or online college games certain
companies uh to propose and then they
can move as fast as they want through
the process uh but but this is this is
uh this is a way to for for us to be
able to engage with the world and then
on board these applications oncology
efforts
right so there's a couple of other
things that are unfortunate here
um in terms of of some ongoing
contributions so we have several large
digital multimedia forensic extenders
uh we have uh
very very soon
um we have a UCO graph Exchange Server
and so this will uh this will be a tool
that you can download from GitHub and
you can upload uh your answer engage
with oncology uh
represented in in Json LP and This
Server will basically let you upload it
and set through and query it and
validate it
um there's some other uh some other
significant efforts that are going on uh
the Netherlands forensics Institute they
have a digital forensics as a service
platform
um and so they have been working through
case UCL adoption and we've got some
open source pools autopsy and network
minor that we've been working with uh
and so they have some initial adoptions
and so those are tools that you may
encounter reviews in an academic setting
you know the forensics lab
and then there's some various student
government agencies that are that are
also looking at the options like
um
so finally this is my last slide we have
some product resources if you want to
come visit the project on internet uh
we're at the Cyber domain oncology.org
and that will point you to the unified
cyber oncology our middle ontology and
then it will also point you to the app
the published application oncology so
the case oncology and the adversary
engagement technology
so with that
um I think we're gonna hold questions to
the very end but again thank you so much
for having me here today to talk and uh
the turn it over and out to the heat so
that he and his team can talk about the
adversary
that was a very enlightening
presentation uh both in terms of the
vision of the bullet for the roadmap now
before we move on to the uh to the
address engagement ontology
representation overview
um
Alex Nelson from Nest has ultimately
agreed to present a brief uh statements
introduction overview of his and college
involvement in the project
Alex was wondering if you were able to
uh
share me are you still on the call I see
you now yes yep
and the floor is yours
uh thank you actually the brief
inheritance statement um hello everyone
my name is Alex Nelson I was the
inaugural case ontology committee chair
I'm currently the UC ontology committee
chair and I am also the CDO technical
steering committee Vice chair I
continued to lead development of much of
cdo's resources I'm representative of
the government class of community
members my employers the U.S National
Institute of Science and Technology also
known as nist
uh this mission is to promote U.S
Innovation and Industrial
competitiveness by advancing measurement
science standards and technology in ways
that enhance Economic Security and
improve our quality of life I support
that mission by participating in the
development consensus of Metrology and
the Sciences my efforts at CDO are part
of developing the science and Metrology
of cyberspace thank you for the
invitation
thank you very much
and
um
I think this is now a good time to ask
the sale team
Nancy Rose
um
the presentation file is
over here
thank you
foreign
College of Engineering
uh we
uh work on research projects at the
intersection of cyber security
artificial intelligence complex systems
and cognitive
uh science and Neuroscience
the team that has been working on
developing at the same data applications
is because two of my doctoral students
uh Nancy of Piazza and David and we also
have Ronnie scorpon undergraduate
research assistant
who has been contributing to this effort
uh since its Inception
professor of computer science and data
science and I'm also the principal
investigator of Salem at the University
of New Haven
and I would like to
return the microphone to my wonderful
team to present more of a new uh their
project please welcome the team
thank you to provide hello everyone
um
so let's get started so today what I'm
doing to you about anniversary
investment applications
so
so this is
adoptability fan organic
indicator for the motivation and
objectives behind them and refrigerator
that all the Rosie and the next is going
to cover the aeel's design and an
example of how we can make best use of
it
okay so what is anniversary reasoning
for we are just part of the condition
from the American language
uh explanation
so we want to understand how we can
interact and respond to the administry
in the network so in the abolition way
you can use addressing this might
require an operation using denial and
techniques we can monitor any valid
sources of energy operations and the
goal here is to
how we can actually increase the amount
of operation and decrease the value of
their overall operations right and for
that we can use the relevant Frameworks
of that minor attack we succeeds
now we have that Frameworks in place but
how can we represent this concept in
terms of rock right and this is where
address three engagement
now what is addressing this
it is
focuses on defining and its memorizing
the information preposition of adversary
investment and decide
and
these are the very forces we should
write the overall process of that
surround study we also want to improve
the consistency applying a operations
and we want to make sure that the
evacuation process and communication uh
with defects stakeholders and actors
various Stones is very seamless enemies
and because of that
foreign
right and because of that it contributes
to the ease and consistency of
integrated data force uh between across
the very sermon a cyber operation and it
also helps in the seamless uh a
operation configurations
so ideally we should be able to repair
that all the concepts are used for
accuracy in this thing but we are
limited uh and we right now what we have
done is we have uh we were able to
represent the concept from the existing
address
and also the necessary Concepts from
like that framework uh
so the correct list that we have is uh
we just released our current data
version of a Euro percent 0.1.8 and it's
already in the kicked up and we'll be
looking forward to make more changes and
release the uh more stable and uh with
the property Works in a few months
um
to describe the models in uh design and
process thank you
hi everyone I'm Nancy I'm a PhD PhD
student at this lab I work as primarily
on mobile agents
systems um so me right here we have an
anthology overview this diagram here is
really going to help us see an idea of
the purpose of certain classes or
concepts
um and where they flow and why we
introduce them but we'll break it down
so ideally right as an anthology we have
the actual structure of an ecology where
we have the namespace the name space is
commonly proposed of basically by the
namespaces we have the attack which
referrals to Concepts from Attack
Frameworks
foreign
we have the pre-pro learning ideas and
Concepts things that we really establish
or if you create a plan uh three
ingredient plants and events and plan
events together and then of course we
have the things that populate them which
are the perception of objects of cells
and maybe some operational things the
things
are more or less like the ideas
exclusively absolutely even you probably
wouldn't find them anywhere else most
likely right but the other ones are not
cool maybe Concepts that might overlap
with other
um uh domains right so then we need to
really think about when to depreciate
those Concepts later on or when it kind
of
so please rewinding concepts are are
designed to support the starting minor
engaged headset process for 80 like a
graph right so I either need to use this
repair we reference the entire process
of planning like the entire processary
operational ordinary effects
so expanding the second most important
uh
Japanese space there's really only one
actual class in the same space it's all
objective all the rest of them are
instances of objectives and specifically
why we just outline very specifically
lighter attacks and minor engages
um uh tactics and higher level goals
um which we use actually
and then of course we cover a little bit
of other things which can be considered
like things that are not necessarily get
covered by minor or they could be
exactly that uh we link two of them
together
then we have obviously making sure we
have identity in general so identity uh
under the UCO identity right they have
uh they basically inherit their their
class for that and we considered
something called the Persona and a team
so Persona we usually just decided as a
separation of concepts of identities or
real identities
of people actually are who they're
asking
right
um and then we have a concept of a team
so ideally in uco's identity they have
an organization but we really want to
specify the meal a subset of people who
actually interact directly and
coordinate foreign
the purple team those are all just
okay so moving on uh we talked about
exclusive lineatology
of a positive quality and now we need to
talk about the usages and the intentions
of wider and such designs and mostly and
the best way they can really give you an
idea why is divided into phases of when
you when you process information this is
the pre-operation phase like the
pre-planning phase interoperation days
when during an operation during time
what was actually happening and why are
you modeling and impulse operation which
is more or less the analysis
so
the pre-operation and implying of an
operation is important to be able to
start to represent right this is kind of
like uh your first blueprint you know
and so it's one of the tools that we
have here from the planning segment on
the need engage right we need to express
a sequence of events plan events
together
um that relate to some sort of ordering
of expectation of how a particular uh
operation is going to go right so we
need to see we need to be realistic um
and have actual concrete discussions of
how of our expectations and we need to
expect to development of resources prior
to an operation
so the narrative concepts are there
really support this for this um
intra operation
um it occurs during an operation so
before it comes after the pre-planning
and during when an operation X is
actually run into its termination so
that's what we really call
interoperation
there are some things during planning
right um when you plan things like if
you have an actor in a particular
environment right by Defender has active
persona it's not something you can
deploy before the operation right it's
actually somebody who actually interacts
during an operation information
will probably come from data sources for
monitoring logging right so when you
monitor a particular network activity
right you might be able to have other
information
so it's usually there to help you get an
idea of what exhibitions can you expect
for certain phases of what the
permissions look at the information down
the properties
right and then finally there's post
operation right we really addressed
pre-operation in
the pre-planning major operation
Concepts and we are exposed there so we
have generation however post operations
are also very complex
right
um post operation phase and unsettable
usages
namely like directly that we address we
address minority we just understand
um right and so that's kind of more or
less a starting the process of the
processing information
um reducing information and then
including up with a new plan for
reiteration right but then it's also
identifying when modifications or
Corrections are made to build a timeline
evidence
closet
um we are currently going to quote for
supporting evaluation and measurement of
interoperation measurements test so
during an actual measured right is there
a measure that you can take during
measure to determine how well your
operations
so more or less right you have a plan
and then you start uh
you perform the operated and then you
align your that's together
okay and then finally the best part of
this um to really enumerate how you can
use apps on
ology
so of course um mentioned this home
alone but we all mentioned it again
because it really is a good example of
how it is and the
um you know a Labyrinth of many little
booty chats
um so obviously the idea is if you can
see that battle plan that came and wrote
up right and in some way right it's a
blueprint it's basically kind of like
the concept The Narrative except maybe a
little bit more information he doesn't
really tell you the secret events that
he expects to happen but a lot of that's
actually really important to encode in
during the planning place right and then
of course we have this little senior
word yeah people dancing pretend to give
it a perception and there are people
living and being Lively in the house
even though there was none so right a
lot of Engagement depends on something
perception which is really important to
actually identify in an intelligence
okay so here specifically we're going to
call ourselves uh we have a company
called mineral R Us right
so we're a small yet critical rare herb
Mining Company in New Hampshire
our main clients are from the critical
infrastructure technology in the events
Industries
our key intellectual properties and
operational procedures are stored on
paper
fashion and this is only known by
celebrity
but we do have a small unorganized
computer network but only generic
security infrastructure we have every
small team that operates uh that
contains operational Technologies
and we just received an advisory notice
some of the federal authorities that
there are rapidly growing cyber threats
as acknowledged by state sponsored apts
that are more frequently
um so in response right your company
decides to engage an external type of
security provided to a certain way
timely incident response and prevention
the external provider recommends the
employment
and asks you to develop a high level
deception and denominable strategy
so
mentioning that a little bit from at a
certain engagement we pull from this
very useful tool the back depiction uh
the nylon deception Matrix right so we
have path along the column side we have
the perception techniques uh deception
and denial type is on the
so the idea here is is like here so over
here a fact you know that we have what
we want to reveal is the network is in
New Hampshire the business runs a mine
in New Hampshire so that's more or less
something being covered and so that we
want them to confirm so that they feel a
little more uh secure in their
assumptions then maybe for a position
that we want to tell them or reveal to
them right is that we have low value
intellectual properties stored on the
network right
and then we have the slack which is for
the concealing like the things that we
want to we want to conceal form
Anonymous series of things that we want
to protect we have a business
relationship with strategic Partners
have a minerals money from the Strategic
Partners uh process reminding uh that is
essential to them right and the amounts
of mineral minds all that information as
well as like the company's location
saying passcodes
um or anything like that right so those
are really good things we really want to
connect and then for the fiction uh that
we want to quote conceal we want percent
uh we want the conceal is that most
important intellectual property is
located in this specific location
so
we have a Serial engagement all the
improvised structure needed to transform
your abstract deception concept plan
into representation the degree of how
being still your narrative will depend
on how extensively refined you want to
be opportunity planning to be right so
you may come out with this 100 page the
century plan all written and lots of
paragraphs and words and a lot of detail
right but now you need to conversions
and sometimes you might realize hey I'm
actually missing some information
um
so this is more or less dependent on how
much resources you're willing to put out
uh right and if it's not right then you
repeat until you're satisfied
so to start off right first thing we do
is we create a narrative The Narrative
is just kind of like your discussion
campaign
um so you are a lot so you're able to
actually distinguish the differences
between a plan and the rest of the unit
right so then you create your plan
events there's one specifically has two
plan events and you can kind of see the
relationship one comes first the next
comes after right so the storyline Falls
the structure of the museum acts threads
to The Chronic parsley organ sets
so if we expand the first line events at
the center we have an action so this is
basically like the evidence that you
action right
um what we call actions is it action and
then this action has very specific
properties that inherits a uco's action
is such as like the performer the
objects
um maybe even like the environment and
those kind of things so the performer of
the deploy action is this particular
person and then what do they deploy what
object to manipulate they deployed
and so there's a very specific
um special property which is called has
characterization which links up the
concepts right the concept of AE so the
physical world of what observables are
supposed to represent so this Honeypot
is going to be you know on an actual
system a maybe a device and it's going
to have this particular running server
operating system or so forth right and
so those alert objects like what does it
actually look like it actually the
characterization of it is actually a PDF
or their oscillated thoughts
so this relationship can be built out
right so this plan that moral is just
told you that a person that deployed a
bunch of deception objects
files the configuration of the data
sources so the second thing that
happened in this particular event is
that uh this person deployed right
another data source system for setting
up like you know this security
monitoring
then comes the second event so we expand
the second event they all kind of
language so you can get the operations
right it describes a scenario which
follows the first planned event
um
and then we have the canary token is a
server data source did they Source alert
so it's got certain files of access on
or off to them
and then this is just literally just an
overview of how it looks together
it's kind of release
technically but uh if you start putting
all the arrows in right then it'd be
starting
so
um one of the most important
um usage of an intology is to query uh
from the graph information but what kind
of information can we get from
standardization process for example
let's just load into
um
so maybe I have a question I want to
know about how many deception objects
were instantiated with a particular
objective which is Consulting well you
can tell me too why because actually
there's only two also be a scary
thoughts right there being um
so the Honeypot and maybe the files
right then we have direct and we have a
sculpture those are the two options
right
um May provide some Logistics that will
not immutable impairment phrase right
maybe you want to diversify or narrow
the deception techniques depending on
the type of adversary you expect right
so maybe report adversaries in your wine
or Niche right a very particular
purposes for certain types of
um
um actions right or certain types of
um right so therefore maybe you want to
eat a dangerous plant where Sun Fighters
your spread
um your AE objective goals right
um to really cover and be more a little
bit more resilient towards those
specific kinds of attacks
and then future developments
intelligence we have
so challenges are as followed right as a
as an application oncology right uh we
need to stay compliant with them at all
times at least under official versions
and their full versions right so that's
really important sometimes UCO has some
big structural changes that also will
change ourselves uh we work for
facilitating students and options of
current tools and techniques
then we have to pick and choose which
Concepts that overlay between domains
and figure out who gets to own that
concept and who really should become
responsibility of it right and you may
need to possibly conflict Resolute uh
Concepts when they are so for example a
lot of things we borrowed from CTI
um you know leave this there and live
there but we may want to use them
and of course we want the game to be
compatible with other relevant
applications
um this is where you can find uh our
particular repository uh where you plan
your ecology for what sign is equal we
support uh if you want to contribute you
can also contact those this year
um
and then we did a small little uh test
thank you according for uh showing this
um we asked dbt4 about what information
could it gather by giving it just to
Json LD format right
is very very smart about
um describing some of the things that
are concentrated right so objective
storyline events it's a really good idea
of what we're trying to present in this
Json something is wrong but
um it's a really interesting thought
that you know you could be promised even
just by uh publishing or anyone
and so these are the contributors are
still up and then from the minor team
that a lot of input of them which is
extremely helpful we were Guided by a
lot of people on the miter teams of the
direction for you based on Direction
so I also and I like any questions
thank you very much
wonderful presentation I'm going to open
the floor to what uh questions from the
audience but before doing this I just
wanted to add something to the very last
slide that you had before the relative
page on the GBP board sample so last
night I had a little bit of trouble uh
sleeping I got to play around with gpt4
and our ontology
now that's
well
um gpt4 in the channel
or Chad gbt 3.5 has seen this example of
Json lb you can then ask it to convert
the textual description
into a Json and that's one of the things
that we are going to explore as
one application or at least uh one uh
tool that is built on top of this work
there's the scope of utilization
adoption and expansion and extensions
quite wide and large and promising
particularly when it comes to automation
with that I would like to thank you
again and I would like to open the for
the questions from the audience if you
are online please feel free to raise
your hand if you are in person
uh
praise your political actual and and the
questions are not necessarily have to be
limited to the final presentation
uh I believe whereas and Alex are still
with us employees with us in the bedroom
so
the
while you're waiting for questions I can
go first
so
um
in the industry the cyber security
industry
who and what sort of
development or service provider to be
able to immediately the
AE application
um so primarily right one of our
particular Department Of Interest or our
new audiences is basically the creators
the managers of the studying technology
so there are a bunch of vendors
which produce uh these you know
handy-dandy tool tips for deception
Operating Officer engagement right it'd
be really useful for them to add support
to exporting their information from
their systems into some representations
and that might be really useful for one
transplant information over to other
departments and other people have other
businesses to analyze in that data the
two also keeps standardized
Asian and CM
do we have any questions from the online
audience we are watching your camera
view
like this you've done such a great job
in exactly your work you are absolutely
so I'm going to ask another question to
get the ball rolling I'm sorry again
even to me who's been involved in uh the
development
um
so I remember we had to go through
multiple revisions uh our design for
hematology classes and so on
if
um what are the major concerns in terms
of the calming provisions and their
alignment and compatibility with UCO
if you think the user Community should
be aware managing on ions
um from what I know
proposal are going to be implemented or
are on sale or some of the properties
are going to full cover
um
it's going to cover some other Concepts
that we they initially had alternative
for but then we had to remove it because
it would probably the design process or
integrated use
um so it really depends we kind of
standardize our productology based on
UCO 1.00 version right and so we want to
keep that main support from that if they
you still come out with another visual
version of Standard Version or something
like that they will have to go back and
revise that didn't come up um
still use the first version right but be
aware that so many differences when you
try to use a newer version of you so
thank you
still new questions can we keep going I
have menu
uh if somebody respond to that um
hi uh folks Nelson again
um speaking on my roles UCL ontology
committee chair
um
when UCO released its 1.0 version back
in uh I think it was September of last
year uh we made a commitment to follow
semantic versioning uh specifically
September 2.0 uh you can see it's
semper.org
um that commitment is that we will not
introduce backwards incompatible changes
until the next major release and by
operational Rhythm that release was
going to be planned for if we were in a
crunch and found something horrible six
months uh that'll be about next week
um we are not finding such a an urgent
need for a 2.0 right now so we are
planning at around a year uh we would do
um our first uh 2.0 release introducing
backwards incompatible changes so
anything that you see in version 1.0 or
1.1 so on right now or 1.2 coming out in
the next couple weeks um anything you
see in there will still work with uh
shackle validation uh so the conformance
checking system until our 2.0 release
and with our first backwards and
compatible change set after the December
1.0 release we'll have like a discussion
among the ontology committee uh we're
going to flag something as a warning
when do we start flagging as an error
we've had some people say we need a year
for our engineering teams uh before you
say it's an outright error
um that kind of feedback is what we look
forward to getting from the community as
we plan for our Tour release uh so uh
ants if there is something that comes in
as a potential new feature it might step
on your toes uh because you said I
really wanted that but if it's available
in UCO it's available to the broader
application space as well so
um it's actually someone to be benefited
to have something uh implemented further
Upstream uh for availability purposes uh
but if we do get something that does
look like it's in the middle layer
instead of the application layer it's
good to know that we're actually meeting
the application where the needs
go ahead
uh good I was being concur with this
Sean Barnum sorry with miter um also
heavily involved throughout founding UCL
a lot of the stuff with CDO and have
been working closely with uh vaheed and
I think all the rest of the team on the
AEO stuff
um I agree with Alex completely as far
as the the semantic versioning and major
changes to UCO causing big changes up
into AEO I I would suspect it's likely
the changes that ACO that might triple
are probably going to be more along the
lines of some of the concepts that don't
currently exist in UCO but likely should
for AEO and other Pros doing so the
concept is objective that's something
that's needed by lots of different
application domains but it's not there
right now so AEO has defined it
internally right now there's things like
that there's some of the things that
will be part of the CTI applications I
mean ontology and that could uh
submitted in as just like a CEO is so
it'll likely be things like that that
when there is the more natural place for
that concept to be defined either in UCO
or a different application ontology it
would be simply a matter of within AEO
can still deal with that concept it's
primarily its namespace that would
change so right so the namespace for
that concept you would just reference it
from UCO references from like CTI and it
shouldn't structurally change anything
but it would probably cause a little bit
of a ripple up on hey well now you guys
you know ADM no longer has to worry
about being the native uh Keeper of the
torch for one of those things that
really primarily belongs somewhere else
you would be able to reference and use
it from somewhere else I think that's
likely to be more of the changes that
triple up rather than anything big
structural UCO stuff like like Alex was
saying where the governance is trying to
keep those thanks to a minimum right
especially as more application of
manitologies come in those sorts of
ripples become ways very quickly so the
government in this process is very much
intended to minimize that
foreign
one of the things that you should
consider is joining you know kind of
like joining one of these open source
projects it doesn't have to be cyber
domeology project although a little
biased maybe you should
um but you know while you're in school
and you're studying uh for four six
eight years maybe more sometimes it's
good to get out and take part in these
these efforts where you can collaborate
and you can learn new things you can
apply the skills that you're learning
here in the University it also gives you
the ability to meet lots of people from
you know from industry made by mentors
there you may find Future employers
there you may find Future technical
collaborators there
and and so you know over the years uh
with the with this ongoing engagement uh
with with the University of New Haven uh
we've actually had a number of students
over the years from UNH having
participate in this in this open source
community
um so the the offer is still open for
any students that are interested in
coming and joining
um and so you know like what what might
we be looking for
um well
certainly we're looking for uh computer
scientists to come and join our adoption
committee
uh they're uh there's definitely a big
demand uh we need uh uh essers we need
people to help us just manage concepted
owners uh we need people to help us
manage change just just managing change
proposals as they come in
um and uh and there's a myriad of other
of other things and so that's not what
you saw today if you see something in an
interview like hey I'm really interested
in that one thing Corey talked about I
mean it's talked about what I'm ready to
talk about
just raise your hand and say hey I'd
like to maybe give one hour a month you
know to volunteer for this or two hours
long or something
um you certainly can work that with with
your faculty members uh to maybe
incorporate that into uh Focus study
um and also if you're interested in
contributing uh or or helping recruit
other oncology efforts uh that you might
know about to come enjoy December uh we
certainly would but would welcome that
uh so just a concept but if anyone have
any questions about that sort of thing
about how you might be able to
participate
no
no uh the Linux Foundation uh projects
are completely open to the entire world
so no matter who you are where you come
from
uh you're more than welcome uh
one of the I would say you should at
least be a fairly conversant English
language
uh that's that's probably about the only
requirement just because the rest of the
community operates within English
language but but outside of that they're
really hard no hard requirements
in wonderful Avenue of opportunities to
explore and thank you for that great
right
um I believe there are no other
questions so I can't I can't explain
myself I need to ask one more
Nancy
um for those who are following this live
or those who are watching this little
coordinator on
where can you go and what they have
access to to start playing around with
the current version
it was available
our website
outlines are in our motivations can I
give you a link for our positive
repository we have an example you can
run through the access tutorials right
so there's a small explainable
uh follow up like walk through
documentation that shows you how each
particularities
what the purposes of specific classes
and homes who really is managing these
responses into design we have three
examples and then we have
them
um
we also have generating from uh homicide
or unboxing which generates automated
docs for our our on policy so you can
check that out too so if you want to you
know short planes to be able to go and
see what cool classes are there or what
are specifically you know how to use so
far what's available to you right you
can just do that too UCO also uses it um
thank you very much Nancy
um let's just thank all the speakers of
the day spent one more time
to uh
to Alice
everyone else who helped with putting
the seminar together
um
circulation Anthology we are going to go
out and
spread the warrants and
um
we have an easier polls coming hopefully
we'll have more Asian coming but what it
would really appreciated is feedback and
engagement from the industry as well as
research and academic Community called
role this uh effort thank you everyone
and have a great day
thank you thank you
thank you